# **RESUME**

### **SUDARSAN PIDUGU**

Phone: +91 8464002165 Email: <u>sudarsan2165@gmail.com</u>

Having around 2 years of experience. Linux Administrator and Python Full Stack Developer Technologies with establishing and performing activities over the weekends. In VMware Building server, Disk management, and Troubleshooting.

# SKILLS & ABILITIES:

•Operating Systems : Redhat Linux, Windows

•Monitoring Tool : Nagios

•Network Services : NFS, FTP, SSH, SAMBHA

·Volume Management: LVM

•Other Skills : VMware, AWS, Troubleshooting, Python, Django, UI, MySQL, GitHub.

•Environment : VS Code, Putty, Mobaxterm.

•Portfolio ID : https://sudarsanpidugu.github.io

#### WORK EXPERIENCE:

\*FULL STACK DEVELOPER | FREELANCER | AUGUST 2024 - TILL

### Developer Roles & Responsibilities:

- Attending client class for upcoming changes
- Developed web application back-end components while communicating with clients to identify their needs/goals and work on meeting them.
- Worked on the improvement of data protection and security, increasing the security rate by 24 % while creating new user information solutions.
- Good Analytical and Problem-Solving Skills, Talented team player, quick in learning and adapting to new situations, configurations, and technologies.

# \*SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INERN | AARAM IT SOLUTIONS | OCTOBER 2023 – APRIL 2024

# **Certified Python Developer Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Attending meetings for upcoming changes and understanding team scope
- Developed web application back-end components while communicating with clients to identify their needs/goals and work on meeting them.
- Worked on the improvement of data protection and security, increasing the security rate by 24 % while creating new user information solutions.
- Maintained large databases and configured services to reduce software maintenance expenses, decreasing the costs by 15% within just one year.
- Good Analytical and Problem-Solving Skills, Talented team player, quick in learning and adapting to new situations, configurations, and technologies.

ETL operations project for converting data from different databases into one database and sending final data into a data warehouse this technique is mostly used in software companies, D-marts, etc.... For this project, I used Python technology and the pandas module.

# \*LINUX ADMINISTRATOR & SUPPORT | SRL GLOBAL | OCTOBER 2022- JUNE 2023

- Attending meetings for upcoming changes and understanding the Linux team scope
- Experience in resolving Server down issues.
- Troubleshooting and fixing user unable to login issues.
- Monitoring server health using inbuilt tools like top and SAR
- Installing and upgrading packages using YUM & RPM.
- Disk management, creating File system and troubleshooting disk issues like filesystem full and filesystem usage.
- LVM management Creating, extending, removing the LVs and VGs etc.
- Troubleshooting while LVM is corrupted.
- Working with other teams for login/permissions-related issues
- Monitoring System Resources like CPU utilization, Virtual memory, and SWAP utilization.
- Increase the Swap Space online as per client requirements.
- Configuration of FTP and remote applications like SSH, and telnet. Resolving the user login issues.

### PROJECTS:

• Min-hlsning US Client (Freelance)

**Description:** Web application for clients in the US to keep their business growing. https://github.com/sudarsanpidugu/Min-hlsning.git (VS code, UI Technologies(HTML, CSS) and GitHub).

• E-Commerce online shopping (Aaramit solution)

**Description:** E-commerce application for the clients of Aaramit Solutions to keep track of their Products, Product Stocks, and order tracking from multiple regions.

(VS code, Python, Django Framework, MySQL, UI Technologies).

• Data Analysis (Self project):

**Description:** ETL operations project for converting data from different databases into one database and sending final data into a data warehouse this technique is mostly used in software companies, D-marts, etc.... For this project, I used Python technology and the pandas module. https://github.com/sudarsanpidugu/Data-Analytics.git (VS code, Python, Pandas, Numpy, MySQL, Excel, Notepad, Oracle, MSSQL).

• Student Management System (Self project):

**Description:** Developed a robust Student Database Management System leveraging Python programming and MySQL database integration. This project mainly aimed to perform all DML commands on data taken.

<u>Url:- Python-Projects/GUIproject/NthStudentsData.py</u> (VS code, Python, MySQL, Tkinter). Etc...

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

 Degree BSc (Computers) from Dr. Br Ambedkar University Hyderabad from Govt Degree college for men (2018-2021) passed with 7.11 CGPA